

Kuttikattu Parambil (H), Anakkara, Palakkad,Kerala 679551

□ (+91) 9895980223 | 36rahu@gmail.com | 36rahu | 3rahul-k-p | 1 rahulank

Summary_

Python developer specialized in Web technology. Experienced in all the stage of development cycle for project. Well-versed in multiple programming languages including Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS etc. Strong background in project management and customer relations. Active contributor on stackoverflow.

Work Experience _____

Tarams Software Technologies Pvt Ltd.

Bangalore

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2017 - PRESENT

Tarams is a technology consulting and product engineering company that helps clients transform their mission-critical business applications to digital platforms. Tarams takes an agile and collaborative approach across the value chain and provides you a strategic advantage.

- Algo to you (Tech stack: Python, Flask, Postgres, Redis)
- Truelink financial scraping (Tech stack: Python, Scrapy, Shell script.)
- LinkedIn Crawler (Tech stack: Python, Java, PostgreSQL, Lamda, EC2, RDS)
- Social Capital Document Portal (Tech stack: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, AWS (EC2, S3, SES, Lambda)).

Oxxus Technologies Private Limited

Mumhai

SR.PYTHON DEVELOPER

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2017

The company has been dealing with various crowdsourcing projects. They have a small technical team to help with the internal tools. I was being part of that team. I got the opportunity to work with different projects such as Resume parser, Static website generator and etc.

- Resume Parser (Tech stack: Python, Django, ML, NLP, Mysql.)
- Static website generator (Tech stack: Python, Jinja2, Django, S3, Route 53)

Castalia Research Labs Private Limited.

Pune

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Dec. 2014 - Mar. 2016

Experience in developing customized industrial automation and vision systems, utilizing a wide range of vision hardware and software. Involved in design, development, installation, commissioning and validation of the vision systems at the customer's site and machine builder facility.

• Industrial automation system (Tech stack: Python, Raspberry PI, GPIO programming)

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python, Javascript

FRAMEWORKS

Django, Mezzanine, Flask, Scrapy

FRONTEND

HTML, CSS

DATABASES

MySQL,Postgresql

SOURCE CODE MANAGEMENT

Git, GitLab, Github

CLOUD SERVICES

Amazon web services (EC2, S3, SES, Lambda, RDS, IAM, Route 53, Redis)

OTHERS

Machine Learning, Image processing, Raspberry Pi, GPIO programming, Jinja2, Shell script



Algoto you

Nov 2018 to May 2019

An application used to purchase building materials from Home Depot stores and various Suppliers.

- · Actively contributed to the backend which is developed in Python flask and Postgres using microservice architecture.
- · Also, Integrated different third-party applications such as Braintree, Sendgrid, Firebase, Twilio and etc.
- I also created various APIs and different services such as Promotion service, Admin service, Order service, User service, Picker service, Driver service and etc.

Truelink financial scraping

May 2019 to July 2019

It's a small scraping project which scrapes information from a different website and stored in a CSV format. There are different 7 types of the website need to scrape and store the scraped information in the CSV file. There is one top script written in the shell script to run all these websites altogether.

- Worked as a senior developer in this project
- Involved in the design and development of the codebase.
- Also, have the responsibility to guide the junior developer as well the review their code.

LinkedIn Crawler

Mar 2018 to Sep 2018

LinkedIn crawler includes three modules such as the Google Scraper, LinkedIn scraper, and LinkedIn Parser. The Google scraper list out LinkedIn profiles of users in a particular company. LinkedIn scraper downloads those profiles using microleaves services. And Linkedin parser will parse the profile page and store the details in the database. Worked as a full-stack developer for this project.

- Developed and modified the code to scrape the LinkedIn website.
- Involved to design the architecture for the crawling and scraping modules.
- Worked with microleaves service for the proxy of the server.
- Deployed the modules in different AWS services such as AWS Lambda, EC2, and RDS.

Social Capital Caas Automation

Aug 2017 to Jan 2018

It's an automation portal that receives data from type form and populates to Podio. Involved in backend development for the application and the project flow design and database model design. Worked with Podio API integration with the backend. Helped to integrate with the frontend and backend. Also involved for the deployment of codes in amazon web services.

- Involved in backend development for the application.
- · Worked with Podio API integration with the backend.
- Involved in the project flow design and database model design.
- Involved the deployment of codes in amazon web services.

Resume Parser

July 2016 to Feb 2017

Resume parser is an application to convert the pdf resume into JSON format. Developed in Python using Scikit Learn, Nltk, Django and Html parser. Resume parser is used by recruitment companies to process resumes to find the best resume from a list of resumes. Involved in algorithm design, project flow, project coordination and an end to end coding.

- · Involved in algorithm design, project flow, project coordination and the end to end coding.
- Studied different technologies and their implementation in the project.
- Involved in the implementation of front-end to interact with the users.

Tarams corporate website migration

Jan 2018 to Mar 2018

Tarams corporate website migration to an editable admin website. Work involved developing backend required to the website make editable from admin for easier administration of the website. Developed database models required to store the content.

- · Work involved developing backend required to the website make editable from admin for easier administration of the website.
- Developed database models required to store the content.

Static website generator

Mar 2017 to June 2017

Static website generator is like a CMS in Django. The project helps clients to generate a static website by simply filling a form. The generated static website will be automatically be deployed in the AWS. Involved in end to end development including front-end backend and written automation script to deploy the static website on AWS S3 and Route 53.

- Involved in end to end development including front-end backend.
- Automation script to deploy the static website on AWS S3 and Route 53.
- Wrote the jinja2 template script to generate the static website.

Industrial automation system

Mar 2017 to June 2017

This was an automation process to check the presence of raw material in the manufacturing process. The automation system was built using a Raspberry Pi, Camera, and Object detection sensor.

Education

MES College of Engineering(University of Calicut)

Kuttippuram, Kerala, India

B.Tech. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2010-2014

Govt. Higher Secondry School

Govt. Higher Secondry School

Kumeranellur, Kerala, India

2010

PLUS TWO(PCM WITH BIOLOGY)

Anakkara, Kerala, India

SSLC

2000

Extracurricular Activity _____

- Active member in Stackoverflow.
- Have some open source contribution in Github.
- Undergone 3 months training course "Programing as Engineering" conducted by TheLycaeum, Calicut.
- Organized and volunteered several workshops and events under IEEE and MATRICS(CS organisation).
- Participated in several workshop events under IEEE and MATRICS(CS organisation).

Personal Skills

- · Ability to make friendship quickly.
- Confident and honest.
- Excellent co-ordination skills.
- collaboration with other team members.